illumina.com 2019-10-06

# Corporate Privacy Policy

  1. #### Overview

This Illumina Corporate Privacy Policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) explains how information that may be collected from you may be used. This information may be collected in connection with your doing business with Illumina, including for example, your use of this website (“ **Site** ”) or your use of our products or services (“ **Products** ”).

Some examples of our Products include:

    * Cloud-based Software as a Service (“ **SaaS** ”) products used to analyze data and to provide laboratory information management, among other uses.
    * Instruments and reagents used to genotype or sequence DNA.
    * Software installed on customer computers used to analyze data and to provide laboratory information management, among other uses.
    * Information System hardware (e.g., servers, storage, processors) used in conjunction with our products.
    * Genotyping or sequencing services.

In this Privacy Policy the terms “ **Illumina** ”,“ **we** ”,” **us** ”, and “ **our** ” refers to Illumina, Inc. and its affiliates and subsidiaries globally.

  2. #### Illumina is a Global Company Headquartered in the U.S.

Our headquarters is in the U.S. You acknowledge and consent that any information you provide or we may collect may be used, processed, and transferred to the United States and other countries or territories and that those countries or territories may not offer the same level of data protection as the country where you reside. A list of Illumina’s global offices is available at [www.illumina.com](http://www.illumina.com/) for reference.

  3. #### What’s Not Covered by This Privacy Policy?

Some of our business activities, products, or services may involve:

    * Testing of clinical specimens that result in the creation of patient test reports (such as in one of our clinical testing laboratories).
    * Genotyping or sequencing services for research purposes (such as in the course of clinical research or supporting our customers and business partners).
    * The receipt, creation, or analysis of genomic or other data derived from people (such as through customer’s use of our Software as a Service products).

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any samples, data, or information received by us, or created or maintained by us, as a result of the above activities, other than the personal information of business contacts of our customers and partners involved in these activities.

  4. #### Applicability of Other Illumina Privacy Policies

The websites of Illumina’s affiliates and subsidiaries may have separate privacy policies and terms of use that apply to their use. Additionally, some of our Products may have separate privacy policies and terms of use that apply to their use.

  5. #### Information We Collect

We collect various types of information from you, including information you voluntarily provide us and information we get from your use of our Site or Products. For instance, in order to access certain portions of the Site, order Products, or even use some Products you may be required to first register with us. You may be asked to provide your contact information (e.g., name, institution/company, address, phone number, email, username, etc.).

Information we collect about your use of our Site or Products may, for example, include:

    * The Internet Protocol (“IP”) address of your Internet Service Provider.
    * The content you access.
    * The functions, products, or services you use on the Site or Products and purchasing history.
    * Your computer’s operating system.
    * Up-time and other usage statistics about the Site or Products.
    * Location information.
    * Your computer’s unique identifier (e.g., CPU serial number).
    * Web browser used.

The date and time of your visit to the Site or use of the Product.

  6. #### How Collected

Some of this information is collected through your voluntary submissions of information. Some of this information is collected through the use of cookies, which may be placed onto your computer. Some of this information is collected through other technologies (e.g., Google Analytics, WalkMe, Adobe Analytics, Mixpanel, New Relic). The Site or other Products may also use cookies to store user-provided information during your sessions. You can usually set your browser to reject cookies or to alert you before one is placed, if you prefer, but this may mean that you cannot use all features of the Site or the Products.

  7. #### How We Use the Information We Collect

We may use the information collected:

    * To improve the Site, the Products, including any applications, products, services, and software available through them.
    * To improve the customer experience.
    * For marketing purposes.
    * To store your interests and preferences in order to customize your use of the Site or Products.
    * To communicate with you (such as for product support and billing issues).
    * To verify compliance with the terms of use, license, subscription agreement or other agreement governing the use of the Site, the Product, or other of our products or services (“ **Terms of Use** ”).
    * To authenticate users.
    * To improve other of our products and services.
    * To compile and analyze trends.
    * To carry out transactions in connection with you.
    * We also may aggregate the collected information with information from other customers and users of the Site, Products, or other products and services for analysis such as to determine user and performance trends. Generally, any such aggregation will involve de-identified or anonymous data.
  8. #### Google AdWords Remarketing

We use Google AdWords Remarketing to advertise across the Internet. AdWords Remarketing will display relevant ads tailored to you based on what parts of our sites you have viewed by placing a cookie on your machine. This cookie does not identify you. As an example, it could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site such as an incomplete contact form.

If you do not wish to participate in our Google AdWords Remarketing, you can opt out by visiting [Google's Ads Preferences Manager](https://googleads.g.doubleclick.net/ads/preferences/getcookie?sig=ACi0TCi-Cb_kfD1WlwbgDDJYuhcwma6LPPZr7vz3VgpGP5kQZzbsMIoBcekNMSBiYCDMuJui-sjD&continue=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS9zZXR0aW5ncy91LzAvYWRzL2Fub255bW91cz9obD1lbg==&hl=en).

You can also opt out of any third-party vendor's use of cookies by visiting [www.networkadvertising.org/choices](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices).

  9. #### Sharing of Personal Information

As a general rule we do not provide, sell, or lease your personal information to any third parties for their marketing use without your express consent. However, you acknowledge that your personal information may be provided to third parties in connection with your use of their websites, applications, software, or products. We may also share your personal information with contractors, service providers, and other third parties we use to support our business, including without limitation, hosting providers and payment processors. We may also disclose your personal information to third parties: (i) in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal information to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; (ii) if we or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal information will be one of the transferred assets.

  10. #### Collection of Personal Information

You may update and correct your personal information at any time by going to MyIllumina at [www.illumina.com](http://www.illumina.com/). Upon request we will take reasonable efforts to provide you with a summary of your personal information collected by us. If you prefer you can make a request to update, correct, and obtain a summary of your personal information collected by using this [web form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/6f2dfa01-d9cd-48a7-bf63-5e7cc7cb713f).

  11. #### Contacting You

We may contact you as described in this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or applicable contract between us and you or your organization, including as necessary in connection with the Site, the Products, and other products and services you use (e.g., to provide you support, updates to the service, billing issues, etc.).

  12. #### Opt Out

Unless you tell us otherwise by “opting out”, we may also contact you regarding other products and services that may be of interest to you. You can exercise your right to prevent such contact by setting your preferences at MyIllumina at [www.illumina.com](http://www.illumina.com/) or sending a letter to Illumina, Inc., 5200 Illumina Way, San Diego, CA 92122, attention: Legal Department – Website Privacy Policy. Note that you may not opt-out of account management communications (e.g., billing, status emails, support issues).

  13. #### Release of Information

We will release your personal information only if you direct us to do so (such as through a function or feature within the Site, the Product, or other action or communication you make) or as permitted by this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or applicable contract between us and you or your organization. We may also release collected information if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, regulation, court action, to enforce or apply the Terms of Use or applicable contract between us and you or your organization, to prevent abuse of the Site or our Products, or if necessary to protect and defend the rights or property of Illumina, Inc., its affiliates and subsidiaries, employees, customers, or others. We also may be required to disclose your personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

  14. #### Links, Third Party Applications and Software

The Site and the Products may contain links to other sites or may give you access to applications, software, or products provided by third parties (“ **Third Party Sites and Products** ”). Please understand that those Third Party Sites and Products may have different terms of use and privacy policies. You should review those terms of use and privacy policies prior to using them. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of any Third Party Sites and Products. We are also not responsible for the terms of use you may be required to agree to in order to use such Third Party Sites and Products.

  15. #### Retention of Collected Information

We may retain collected information, even after you remove it from the Site or Products, in order for us to comply with law, to enforce any rights in connection with the Site, our Products, or other of our products and services, to use as provided in the this Privacy Policy, the Terms of Use, or applicable contract between us and you or your organization, and to resolve disputes. Collected information may persist indefinitely.

  16. #### Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. When we make changes, we will post the changed Privacy Policy at this site and it will become effective immediately. Your continued access to or use of the Site or Product represents your acceptance of such changed privacy policy.

  17. #### Security of Collected Information

We are committed to protecting the security of the information collected, and we take reasonable physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards to help protect the information from unauthorized or inappropriate access or use. It is your responsibility to protect the confidentiality of your passwords, account information, and any other access features associated with your access or use of the Site or Product as well as adhering to any applicable Terms of Use or other contract between us and you or your organization.

  18. #### Minors

The Site and Products are not directed towards minors and we do not knowingly collect personal information from minors that use the Site or Products.

  19. #### Contact Us

If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact us at: Illumina, Inc., 5200 Illumina Way, San Diego, CA 92122, attention: Legal Department – Website Privacy Policy or at [privacy@illumina.com](mailto:privacy@illumina.com).

Requests for access to or to correct your personal data may be made using this [web form](https://app.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/6f2dfa01-d9cd-48a7-bf63-5e7cc7cb713f).

  20. #### Privacy Shield

With respect to the personal information covered by this Privacy Policy, Illumina, Inc. complies with the EU-US Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework and adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Illumina is committed to resolving complaints or concerns you may have about privacy or how your personal information is used. You may contact us at [privacy@illumina.com](mailto:privacy@illumina.com) or at Illumina, Inc., 5200 Illumina Way, San Diego, CA 92122, attention: Legal Department.

If your complaint is not satisfactorily resolved with us directly, you may contact our independent dispute resolution provider, the International Centre for Dispute Resolution/American Arbitration Association for resolution (<http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html>).

Illumina, Inc. is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) with respect to the Privacy Shield. Under certain conditions you may invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel.

Notwithstanding any language to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, in cases of onward transfer to third parties of personal information of individuals received pursuant to the EU-US and Swiss-Privacy Shield, Illumina, Inc. is potentially liable.

Effective Date: May 25, 2018  
SAP-PLM Doc. 1000000006356
